enphaseenergy.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy | Enphase

### **Privacy Policy**

We have updated our Privacy Policy, effective May 23, 2018

**_Enphase’s Commitment to Data Privacy Protection_**

Protecting the security and privacy of your personal information and data (“Data”) is important to Enphase Energy, Inc. and its subsidiaries worldwide (“Enphase,” “we” or “our”). This Privacy Policy applies to all of Enphase’s activities, in all countries, including our following websites (the “Websites” or “Sites”), all owned and operated by Enphase:

  1. our primary website [enphase.com](http://www.enphase.com/);
  2. our remote monitoring website [enlighten.enphaseenergy.com](http://enlighten.enphaseenergy.com/);
  3. our application programming interface (API) developer website [developer.enphase.com](http://developer.enphase.com/); and
  4. our mobile applications including MyEnlighten, Enlighten Manager, and Installer Toolkit.

To help you to understand our data privacy policies, we have outlined below what Data we collect, how we use the Data, the security measures we use, and with whom we may share the Data. This Privacy Policy also describes your choices regarding use, access, correction and deletion of your personal information. In this Privacy Policy, references to a “Customer” are references to anyone who has purchased Enphase equipment, registered for remote monitoring services, or visited the Sites. The information that we collect will be used to run Enphase business processes, to provide the services that the Customer requests and receives from Enphase, and for the other purposes described below with Customer’s consent which may be withdrawn or revoked by Customer at any time.

**_Information We Collect_**

When you visit our Sites, (for instance, to request Product or installer information, to sign up for newsletters, or to register a product or service), we collect and ask you to provide information about yourself that may include:

  * **Contact details** , including your name, physical address, email address, and phone number;
  * **User ID and password** , if you establish an account with us;
  * **Information about your computer or device** , including browser type and settings;
  * **Log data,** including information like your computer’s IP Address, the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site, pages you visit on our site, time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Site, access times and dates, and other statistics.

**_Questions and Complaints_**

For any privacy questions, issues or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, including making a complaint about our privacy practices, revoking your consent, or requesting correction or deletion of your Data, please contact us at [here](https://enphase.com/en-us/support/contact) or at the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy. We may request that you make any complaint in writing. Enphase will investigate complaints and will notify you of our decision in relation to your complaint as soon as is practical after it has been made.

**_How We Use Your Data_**

Our purpose in collecting Data is to provide you with the best possible user experience for your Enphase system. We may use your Data to:

  * Provide the services and customer support that you request;
  * Send you notices about your system’s energy consumption and production;
  * At your request, create connection between your Enphase account and a third-party service or platform;
  * Customize, personalize, measure, and improve our services, and the content of our website;
  * Send you updates about new products and services that we are offering to customers; and
  * Perform other duties that are required by law.

**_Our Primary Website (“Enphase.com”)_**

When you visit enphase.com, you may be asked to provide personal information including your name, address, telephone number, email address, and type of customer. This type of information is used to improve user experience, respond to inquiries or support requests, and allow us to follow-up after your Site visit.

To receive regular updates regarding Enphase news, products and promotions, you must provide your first name, last name, email address, language preference and country. This information will only be used to send you notifications about Enphase and its products and services, our business partners or to contact you if necessary. You may unsubscribe to this service at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in our notification emails or by contacting us [here](https://enphase.com/en-us/support/contact).

**_Our Remote Monitoring Website (“Enlighten.enphaseenergy.com”)_**

Enlighten.enphaseenergy.com is a separate remote monitoring website (also referred to here as “Enlighten”) which can be accessed from enphase.com. Website visitors’ requests for information about Enlighten and our products which originate on enlighten.enphaseenergy.com are directed back to enphase.com. Our responses to requests for information about Enlighten are internet-based.

When you register for Enlighten, you may be asked to provide your first name, last name, password, a valid email address (used for log-in), a phone number, and your company name and address if applicable. This information is used to establish your Enlighten account, provide you with updates regarding Enphase news, products and promotions, and to contact you about your Enphase system when necessary. If you purchase additional products, we also obtain your credit card and billing information to process the order.

In certain regions, we offer Enphase system owners the opportunity to sign up for third party services that report solar energy production data to other third parties for purposes of enrolling you in incentive programs. If you wish to sign up with a third party provider, you must give Enphase permission/consent to submit certain personal information to the third party service provider, including your name, email address, system location information (street address, city and postal code), meter identifier information (make, model and serial number) and the augmented revenue grade meter data (such as cumulative counter ending value as of the end of the month). We will ask you for this permission/consent when you enter your information on the Enlighten Manager page.

The Enlighten monitoring service uses an automated, internet-based technology called the Envoy/Energy Management Unit (“Envoy”). The Envoy is the networking hub connecting every module and microinverter of an Enphase system to Enlighten monitoring and management software. Once the Envoy is connected to the internet it immediately begins reporting your solar equipment information to Enphase and will continue to do so as long as it is online. By having your Envoy connected to the internet, you consent to this automatic information reporting. The information Enphase receives includes the system’s approximate location based on IP address, its output, efficiency, and other technical variables. Enphase has a legitimate interest to collect, process and store this information in order to monitor and optimize system performance, to conduct remote troubleshooting of systems, and to provide customer service including system updates. This information is recorded and preserved by Enphase on third party data storage facilities which are located in the United States, and is accessible to Enphase at all times. We retain this information on behalf of our Customers for as long as needed to provide necessary services for the Customer, and to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may also use it to improve our products and services, including for quality assurance and engineering performance comparisons.

When you register for Enlighten, the Installer of your system and companies that the Installer may partner with (for example, for solar renewable energy certificate (SREC) reporting services or third party owners if the system is financed through a lease or power purchase agreement (PPA)) are given access to certain Enlighten data, including system consumption amounts and times of usage. This data is used to assist Installers with the installation of our products, troubleshooting, and other system performance related matters. System Owners may remove this access at any time on the Enlighten Settings page. Under certain circumstances, we may share Enlighten data, including latitude and longitude coordinates (“Geo-location”) information, with companies that we co-market, partner, collaborate, or otherwise enter into agreements with. These companies may be located in the United States, in Europe, or elsewhere. You can view and control who we share your Enlighten data with when you log on to Enlighten, or by contacting us [here](https://enphase.com/en-us/support/contact) _._

Enlighten collects information under the direction of its direct customers and may not have a direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. If you are a customer of one of our direct customers (an “End User”) and would like to opt out of certain Enlighten data sharing, please contact the Enphase customers that you interact with directly (in most cases, this is your Installer or Distributor).

If you are an Enlighten Customer, we may ask you to complete surveys or answer questions regarding your satisfaction with any Enphase products you have purchased or services you have received from us. We use this information to improve our remote monitoring services. We may also ask to use information about your experience with our products and services in Enphase’s marketing materials. We will ask for your consent to use such information. The information used will not identify you by full name or address. We will only use the general geographic location (city and state), comments from you, the physical performance data from your solar equipment installation (which is stored on our data storage facilities) and other site-specific information as approved by you.

**_Our API Developer Website (Developer.Enphase.com)_**

Enphase’s API Developer Website is a JSON-based API that gives users access to system performance data and alerts on the Enlighten accounts they have access to. When initially registering, you are required to provide your first name, last name, organization or group name, a username, e-mail address, and a password. Providing a physical address is optional. This information is used to establish your Enlighten Systems API account, and will also be used to provide you with updates regarding Enphase news, products and promotions, and to contact you about your account when necessary. You may unsubscribe to this service at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in our notification emails or by contacting us [here](https://enphase.com/en-us/support/contact).

The Developer Website has a forum that can be accessed only by those who have a valid Enlighten Systems API account. Any information you provide in these forums may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from the forum, contact us at [developeraccounts@enphase.com](mailto:developeraccounts@enphase.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information; if such a situation arises, you will be notified of the reasons why.

**_Our Mobile Applications (MyEnlighten, Enlighten Manager, and Installer Toolkit)_**

With your consent, when you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID").

MyEnlighten and Enlighten Manager are mobile applications that allow Enlighten System Owners and solar professionals to monitor their Enphase systems remotely. To sign in you must provide your existing Enlighten account email address and password. The applications provide a platform to the information already contained in Enlighten, and no additional information is required or collected to use them.

The Installer Toolkit is a mobile application that assists solar professionals with configuring Enphase systems, activating Enlighten accounts, confirming successful installations, and obtaining System performance information. When initially setting up enlighten accounts, Installers may provide the System name, System ID, number of modules, System address, customer name, customer email address, and customer phone number. This information is used to establish your Enlighten account, provide you with updates regarding Enphase news, products and promotions, and to contact you about your Enphase system when necessary.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the mobile application.

**Storage and Security**

The information that Enphase and other permitted third parties collects from you is stored on servers that are located in the United States. We take all reasonable steps to ensure this information is protected from misuse, interference and loss, and from unauthorized access, modification or disclosure.

The security of your Data is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using Secure Socket Layer technology (SSL). Credit card numbers are not retained by Enphase; they are sent to third parties for payment processing. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it; however, no method of internet transmission or electronic storage is 100% secure.

**Ownership of Information and Your Rights**

You own all the information you provide and generate when using Enlighten; however, by providing your consent and using Enlighten, you agree to provide Enphase an exclusive, perpetual, transferable, sublicensable, royalty-free, worldwide license to use this information (for more information, see the “Information Sharing” section below). We may use your Data to conduct market research and analytics, in order to improve the services we offer and to develop new products and services.

**Information Sharing (including for Credit Card payments)**

We will share your Data with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy, in a privacy collection notice provided to you, and only to the extent that you have authorized us to share your Data with third parties. The sections above relating to our Websites also contain details about information sharing specific to each Website.

Enphase is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Enphase may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Enphase may disclose your Data to other Enphase companies and to third party service providers who assist us in providing our products and services, who may be located in the United States and overseas. We contract with other companies and individuals to perform certain functions on our behalf, to provide you with certain services, or to perform analytics that help us understand how Customers use our services and our Sites. This includes processing credit card payments, sending postal mail and email, analyzing data, and providing marketing assistance. These third parties only have access to personal information necessary to perform their intended functions; they may not use it for other purposes; and they must process the information in strict compliance with applicable law. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Privacy Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Customers.

We may use and disclose de-identified data transmitted automatically by your Envoy (used for the Enlighten monitoring service) for any purpose. De-identified data may include energy production and usage, but not your name, telephone number, or email address. Any and all of this information may be anonymized and aggregated with information from other Customers or provided individually as an example of customer experience with our products.

We may sell certain information or data to third parties for non-marketing related purposes including research and development, grid integration purposes, solar resource assessment, product development, and services of our partners and customers. This information may include production, voltage, frequency, and Geo-location information. This information will not contain your name, telephone number, or email address. You may opt out of this use of your Geo-location by logging on to Enlighten and visiting the account settings page, or by contacting us [here](https://enphase.com/en-us/support/contact).

We may also disclose your Data:

  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process;
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request; or
  * If Enphase is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets. You will be notified of this via a prominent notice on our Websites (such as a press release) of any change in ownership or uses of your Data, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Data.

**Access to and Modification of Account Information**

Upon request Enphase will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. Enphase seeks to ensure that all personal information collected and stored in its files and database systems is correct and accurate. Individuals may at any time request access to, or correction of, the personal information Enphase holds about them by contacting us on the details set out at the end of this Privacy Policy. For Enlighten users, once logged on to Enlighten, you can modify account information, including name, address, email address, telephone number and other requested information. If you delete information, we might not be able to provide certain monitoring services to you. If you would like to permanently delete your account or withdraw consent to further contact, please contact Customer Support [here](https://enphase.com/en-us/support/contact). We will respond to your request within 30 days.

Enphase acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. An End User who does not have a direct relationship with Enphase and seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their request to the Enlighten Customer that they interact with directly. If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

**Cookies**

When you access our Websites, we may, with your consent, collect non-personal data through the use of cookies and other similar technologies. This is a quick and convenient method of keeping our Website’s content fresh and relevant to the Website visitor. A “cookie” is a text-only string of characters that is temporarily stored on your device when you access certain websites. Enphase uses cookies to track the pages users visit on our Websites so that information can be customized and enhanced for future sessions. We collect information about the type of internet browser and operating system used, domain name of the website that directed you to our page, number of visits, average time spent on the page, and pages viewed. Our cookies are time-sensitive and automatically expire and deactivate when you close your browser. If the expiration of a cookie is set to be longer than the time you spend on a site, then a text-only string is saved in a cookie on your computer’s hard drive for future reference. The cookies we use cannot retrieve information from your computer’s hard drive, cannot destroy files, and cannot send viruses to your computer. When a cookie is placed on your computer’s hard drive, it does not give Enphase access to any information on your computer, but it may be used to identify your computer. We may use your Internet address (“Internet Protocol address” or “IP address”) and other information collected automatically to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Websites.

Most web browsers allow you to adjust cookie settings. You can still view our Websites if your browser is set to refuse all cookies, but you must enable cookies to log onto Enlighten and make purchases.

**Third Party Tracking Technologies**

With your consent, we allow third parties with whom we have a separate agreement to use cookies and other technologies to collect information about the use of our Websites. These third parties include business partners, who collect information when you view or interact with one of their advertisements on our Websites, and advertising networks, which collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of their advertisements. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about your interests or preferences so that they can display advertisements or promotional material on the Websites tailored to your apparent interests. We do not have access to, or control over, the technologies that these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Please note that you may continue to receive generic ads.

We also contract with selected marketing specialist companies to help us track the effectiveness of our Websites. In conjunction with cookies, we use web beacons to monitor website traffic. A “web beacon” is a graphic on a webpage designed to track pages viewed and messages opened. Web beacons are often invisible, because they are generally only one pixel by one pixel in size. When a user requests an Enphase webpage, the web beacon is retrieved and activated. Once activated, the web beacon can send information to our contracted marketing specialist companies. The information sent includes the IP address of the computer that requested the page, the time the page containing the web beacon was viewed and for how long, and the type of browser that retrieved the page. This information is compiled by our marketing specialist companies and made available to us.

Cookies, together with web beacons, enable us to enhance user experience on our Websites and improve the effectiveness of our advertising. Our contracted marketing specialist companies are not permitted to use this information for any purpose other than the functions which they perform for us.

**Links to Other Sites**

Our Websites contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Enphase. Please be aware that Enphase is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

**Social Media Widgets**

A widget is a stand-alone application that we include on our Websites to display information or invite users to interact in a variety of ways. Our Websites contain various social media widgets including the Facebook “Like” button and the Twitter “Tweet” button, as well as the “Share This” button which allows users to share Enphase content on a number of social media websites.  The Websites also run interactive mini-programs. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Data Retention**

We will retain your Data for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services, as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements, or until you request deletion of your Data. We may retain aggregate, de-identified data to the extent allowed by applicable law. If you wish to cancel or delete your account and you Data, or no longer want Enphase to use your information to provide you services, please contact us using the information below. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

We may change this Privacy Policy periodically to reflect changes to our information practices. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy policy without your explicit consent. We will post all changes to the privacy policy on this page. All changes made to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately upon posting such notice. You will be required to provide or refresh your consent each time the Privacy Policy updates. Please check this privacy policy periodically to make sure that you are aware of our current privacy practices.  By using any of the Websites, you agree to be bound by any such changes and, therefore, you should periodically visit the Websites to examine the then-current Privacy Policy

**Applicable Law**

This Privacy Policy is subject to the laws in the jurisdiction that you are located in.

**Questions or Concerns**

If you have any questions or comments regarding Enphase’s Privacy Policy and your Data, please contact us [here](https://enphase.com/en-us/support/contact), or by phone or mail at:

Enphase Energy, Inc.

1420 North McDowell Blvd.

Petaluma, CA 94954

(877) 797-4743
